## John Hirsch V

US Citizen | St. Louis, MO | jhirschthe5@gmail.com | (757)-344-7496 | jhirschv | GitHub | John Hirsch V | LinkedIn PORTFOLIO

## **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Software developer skilled in Python, Java, and JavaScript. Experience in full-stack web development using Spring Boot, Django, and React. Strong communication and goal setting skills honed from several years working as a personal trainer. Pursuing developer roles in a technical environment.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# BestTech (Java/React Full Stack Web App) BestTech | GitHub

Jul 2024 - Oct 2024

Team Member

- Developed a comprehensive eCommerce application with a fully functioning admin dashboard
- Applied Agile methodologies throughout the Software Development Lifecycle, utilizing Git and GItHub
- Created a product recommendation machine learning algorithm using Python and Scikit-learn
- Utilized Shadon/ui and tailwind to develop a modern user interface

# Train.io (Python/React Full-Stack Web App) Train.io | GitHub

Jan 2024 - Jun 2024

Creator

- Implemented an artificial intelligence powered workout creator through OpenAI's API
- Developed a comprehensive workout journal to track users workout weights, reps, videos, and notes
- Integrated Django REST Framework to create RESTful APIs with data validation to ensure data integrity
- Designed a fully functional personal training system, allowing trainers to manage clients effectively
- Designed an aesthetic dashboard with data visualization for monitoring fitness progress and achievements
  Tech Stack: Python (Django), React.js, PostgreSQL, Tailwind CSS, shadcn/ui
  Tech Stack: Java (Spring Boot), React.js, MySQL, Tailwind CSS, shadcn/ui

### Discourse - Chat Application (Python/React) Discourse | GitHub

Jan 2024 – May 2024

- Created a real time chat application, allowing users to signup and chat with friends
- Used **Django Channels and WebSockets** to manage real time messaging
- Designed an interactive React frontend that is fully mobile responsive
- Integrated JWT Authentication for secure API requests and user logins
  Tech Stack: Python (Django), React.js, Websockets, Django Channels, Libsodium.js

**Cloud Code** — Online Code Execution Project

Jan 2024 - Mar 2024

- Created a web based coding environment that allows users to write code that is executed remotely
- Utilized the **Docker SDK** to spin up **docker containers** to execute user submitted code
- Developed a frontend with React and Material UI, using the Monaco text editor react package
- Tech Stack: Python, Django, Docker, React.js, Tailwind CSS, Material UI

### Social Network - CS50's Web Programming with Python and JavaScript Project

Oct 2023 - Dec 2023

- Developed a social network platform with interactive posts and a follow/follower system
- Utilized Django's ORM to manage user data and interactions with efficient database queries
- Incorporated asynchronous JavaScript API requests for single page application functionality
  Tech Stack: Python (Django), JavaScript, WebSockets

### **SKILLS**

Java, Python, JavaScript, SQL, MySQL, Spring Boot, Django, React.js, Node.js, Git, Docker, AWS, PostgreSQL, MySQL

## **EDUCATION**

Launch Code Web Development - Java Bootcamp Old Dominion University Bachelor of Science St. Louis, Missouri Graduated Aug 2024 Norfolk, Virginia Graduated May 2023